Finding Aid for C. Loring Brace papers, 1954-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Publications
  - "Cultural Innovation and the Mechanism for the Emergence of Modern Morphology,", 1991 (Box 20)
  - "Modern Human Origins: Narrow Focus or Broad Spectrum? The David Skomp Lecture,"1992 (Box 20)
  - "Maximum Human Biological Diversity in the Mesolithic, and the Peopling of the Americas,", 1992 (Box 20)
  - "Craniofacial Continuity and Change: A Comparison of Late Pleistocene and Recent Europe and Asia,", 1992 (Box 21)
  - "Cro-Magnon and Qafzeh: Vive la Diff칠rence,", 1992 (Box 21)
  - "The Great Chain of Being,", 1993 (Box 21)
  - "Clines and Clusters Versus "Race:" A Test in Ancient Egypt, and the Case of a Death on the Nile,", 1993 (Box 21)
  - "The Consequences of Group Selection in a Domain without Genetic Input: Culture,", 1994 (Box 21)
  - "A Four-Letter Word Called Race,", 1994 (Box 21)
  - "Region Does Not Mean "Race:" Reality Versus Convention in Forensic Anthropology,", 1994 (Box 21)
  - "Race,", 1995 (Box 21)
  - "Publish? Or, Perish the Thought!,", 1995 (Box 21)
  - "What Shall We Call "Them"?,", 1996 (Box 21)
  - "Beginnings in East Asia,", 1996 (Box 21)
  - "Evolution in Anthropology,", 1996 (Box 21)
  - "Neanderthals "R" Us,", 1997 (Box 21)
  - "Chain of Being,", 1997 (Box 21)
  - "All that Glitters is not Gould,", 1997 (Box 21)
  - "The Intellectual Standing of Charles Darwin, and the Legacy of the "Scottish Enlightenment" in Biological Thought,"1997, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - "The Peopling of the Americas: Anglo Stereotypes and Native (Box 21)
  - American Realities,", 1999 (Box 21)
  - "Franchthi: Between Asia and Europe, or Qui Erant Danai et per Crania (Box 21)
  - Cogniti Sunt?,", 1999 (Box 21)
  - "The Raw and the Cooked: A Plio/Pleistocene Just So Story, or (Box 21)
  - Sex, Food, and the Origin of the Pair Bond,", 2000 (Box 21)
  - "The Probable Mutation Effect,", 2000-2001 (Box 21)
  - "Peopling of the New World: A Comparative Craniofacial View." In (Box 21)
  - The Settlement of the American Continents: A Multidisciplinary Approach to Human Biogeography. C. Michael Barton, Geoffrey A. Clark, David Yesner, and Georges A. Pearson, eds. Pp. 23--38. Tucson: University of Arizona Press. With A. Russell Nelson and Pan Qifeng. (Box 21)
  - "Old World Sources of the First New World Inhabitants,", 2001 (Box 21)
  - "Humans in Time and Space. In Scientists Confront Creationsim,", 2002 (Box 21)
  - "The Concept of Race in Physical Anthropology,", 2002 (Box 21)
  - "Cooking in Antiquity,", 2002 (Box 21)
  - ""Neutral Theory" and the Dynamics of the Evolution of "Modern" Human Morphology,", 2003 (Box 21)
  - ""Neutral Theory" and the Dynamics of the Evolution of "Modern" Human Morphology,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "Early South Americans in Craniofacial Metric Perspective: Lagoa Santa,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "Race Is Not a Valid Biological Concept. In Is Race a Universal Idea: Transcending the Western Paradigm. Yasuko Takezawa, ed,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "Craniofacial Form and Regional Population Affinities: A Comparative Approach to Paleo--Indian Origins. In Handbook of North American Indians,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "The Questionable Contribution of the Neolithic and the Bronze Age to European Craniofacial Form,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "The Evidence of Teeth, Skulls, Blood and DNA; The Evidence of Language,", 2005 (Box 21)
  - "Do Early South Americans Show Biological Similarity to Australians?,", 2006 (Box 21)
  - "Human Emergence: Natural Process or Divine Creation?,", 2007 (Box 21)
  - "Tooth Size Clines in Australia,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Exploring the Kennewick Connection,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Race: Social Construct vs Biological Reality,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Rebuttal [Biochemical Challenge to Evolution],", undated (Box 21)
  - "Race,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Prehistoric Japan,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Questions About Natufian Role in the Spread of the Neolithic,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Race in American Physical Anthropology,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Science" in the Service of Racism,", undated (Box 21)
  - "A Summary Framework for the Peopling of the New World,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Neandertals: The Source of the Name,", undated (Box 21)
  - "Clusters,", undated (Box 21)
  - Book Reviews
    - 1969-1998 (Box 21)
    - Undated (Box 21)
  - Compton's Encyclopedia
    - 1993 (Box 21)
    - 1994 (Box 21)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Encyclopedia Brittanica, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Encyclopedia of Race and Racism (Box 22)
    - 2005 (Box 22)
    - 2005 (Box 22)
    - 2006 (Box 22)
    - 2007 (Box 22)
    - 2008 (Box 22)
  - Handbook of American Indians, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Yearbook of Physical Anthropology, 1990-1993 (Box 22)
  - "Evolution in an Anthropological View,", 2000 (Box 22)
  - "Man's Evolution: An Evolution to Physical Anthropology,", 1965 (Box 22)
  - "Los Estados de la Evoluci칩n Humana,", 1973 (Box 22)
  - "Race and Intelligence,", 1971 (Box 22)
  - Race" is a Four Letter Word
    - 2002-2005, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Bound volume, 2005 (Box 22)
  - The Stages of Human Evolution
    - 1965 (Box 22)
    - 1967 (Box 22)
    - 1977 (Box 22)
    - 1979 (Box 22)
    - 1986 (Box 22)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 22)
    - 1987 (Box 22)
    - Illustrations, 1987 (Box 22)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 22)
    - Illustrations 4th edition, 1991 (Box 22)
    - 1993 (Box 22)
    - Graphic Materials, 1993 (Box 22)
    - 1994 (Box 22)
    - Bound volume, 1995 (Box 22)
    - 1999 (Box 22)
    - Proofs and Illustrations, undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - 6th edition, 2004 (Box 23)
- Research
  The Research series, 1936/73-2007 (3 linear feet) is made up of two subseries; grant proposals and data. The content of these is made up of research grant proposals either reviewed by Brace or where he was involved as researcher or advisor. These proposals provide a scope of the type of research he was involved in. The data subseries is limited in context documentation for some of the material. Contents include collected raw data, statistical analyses, some graphs and representations. Considerable amounts of this data are measurements of teeth, crania, mandibles, and hominid remains.
  - Grant Proposals
    - American Philosophical Society, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Application for Research in China, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Committee on Scholarly Communication with People's Republic of China, 1980 (Box 23)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1988-1989 (Box 23)
    - Leaky Foundation
      - 1985-2003 (Box 23)
      - 2000 (Box 23)
      - 2004 (Box 23)
    - National Geographic Society, 1988 (Box 23)
    - National Institutes of Health
      - 1968 (Box 23)
      - 1982 (Box 23)
      - 1983 (Box 23)
    - National Science Foundation
      - 1963 (Box 23)
      - 1964-1967 (Box 23)
      - 1967-1974 (Box 23)
      - 1973 (Box 23)
      - 1978-1980 (Box 23)
      - 1978-1995 (Box 23)
      - 1979 (Box 23)
      - 1981 (Box 23)
      - 1982 (Box 23)
      - 1986 (Box 23)
      - 1986 (Box 23)
      - 1988 (Box 23)
      - Final Report, 1990 (Box 23)
      - China Exchange, 1990 (Box 23)
      - 1999, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - 2000 (Box 24)
      - 2004, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - 2005 (Box 24)
      - 2006 (Box 24)
      - 2007 (Box 24)
    - Rackham Grant
      - 1973 (Box 24)
      - 1977 (Box 24)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 24)
      - China, 1983 (Box 24)
      - 1983 (Box 24)
      - 1985 (Box 24)
      - 1986 (Box 24)
    - Paleoamericans Proposal, undated (Box 24)
  - Data
    - Ainu, 2005 (Box 24)
    - African Primates, undated (Box 24)
    - African Tooth Measurements, undated (Box 24)
    - Asia, 1991 (Box 24)
    - Australasia Index, undated (Box 24)
    - Australia-data, undated (Box 24)
    - Australia-teeth, undated (Box 24)
    - Australopithecus and Paranthropus, 1936-1952 (Box 24)
    - Austronesian? -- Range Work, undated (Box 24)
    - Basque, 1988 (Box 24)
    - Chimpanzees, undated (Box 24)
    - Cro-Magnon, undated (Box 24)
    - Dental Data, undated (Box 24)
    - Dental Measurements and Documents, undated (Box 24)
    - Dental Profiles, Drawings, Tables andFigures, 1987-1988 (Box 24)
    - Dentition, undated (Box 24)
    - Dentition Data, undated; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Egypt, 1987-1989 (Box 25)
    - Face, 2003 (Box 25)
    - Japan (Teeth and Data), 1979 (Box 25)
    - Jomon, 2005-2006 (Box 25)
    - KALJ Project, 1988 (Box 25)
    - Krapina Tooth Roots, undated (Box 25)
    - Lagoa Santa, 2004 (Box 25)
    - Language, undated (Box 25)
    - Lapita, 1991 (Box 25)
    - Maps -- North America, undated (Box 25)
    - Maxilla and Mandible Measurements -- Kenyapithecus, Proconsul and others, undated (Box 25)
    - Michigan, undated (Box 25)
    - Minatogawa, undated (Box 25)
    - Molnar, 1991 (Box 25)
    - Discriminant Functions -- Monroe and others, undated (Box 25)
    - National Museum of Natural History, 1989 (Box 25)
    - Neanderthal? Brazil, undated (Box 25)
    - Noses, 1981-1983 (Box 25)
    - Neanderthal -- Notes, A-F, undated (Box 25)
    - Neanderthal -- Notes, G-L, undated (Box 25)
    - Neanderthal -- Notes, M-P, undated (Box 25)
    - Neanderthal -- Notes, S-Z, undated (Box 25)
    - Nile Dendrograms, circa 1993 (Box 25)
    - Okinawa Dendrograms [Midas Output], 1991 (Box 25)
    - Qafzeh, 1998 (Box 25)
    - Race, 1992 (Box 25)
    - Sexing Metrics, undated (Box 25)
    - Teeth Research, undated (Box 25)
    - Teeth Variances -- Coefficient of Variation, undated (Box 25)
    - Teeth Wear, undated (Box 25)
    - Tooth Size Data, undated (Box 26)
    - Upper Cave, 1998 (Box 26)
    - Upper Paleolith, Neolith, Mesolith, undated (Box 26)
- Teaching Materials
  The Teaching Materials series, 1968-2007 (1.5 linear feet) documents Brace's teaching with the Department of Anthropology at the University of Michigan. Materials include syllabi, course schedules, and additional course materials for ANTHRO 161, 566, 471, 661, 670, 701, and his standard fall and winter courses 362, and 570. Also in this series, there is a small amount of correspondence regarding his advising work.
  - Anthro 566, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 563, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 563, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362 A (Winter), 1976 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362 B (Fall), 1976 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 701, 1977 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 560, Winter 1978 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 653, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1980 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 563, 1980 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 161, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 161 (Winter), 1983 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 161 (Fall), 1983 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1983 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 670, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 161, Winter 1985 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1986 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 161, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 564, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1989 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 565, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Core Course Proposal, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 661 (570), 1993 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1993 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 570, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 570, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 570, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 471, Fall 1997 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 570, 1997 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 362, 1999 (Box 26)
  - Anthro 570, 1999 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 570, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2001 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 570, 2001 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2002 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 670, 2002 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2003 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 570, 2003 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2004 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 670, 2004 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 661, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Anthro 362, 2007 (Box 39)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2082 ]
  - Anthro 670, 2007 (Box 27)
  - Darren, Adams, 2005 (Box 39)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2080 ]
  - Billinger, Michael, 2006 (Box 39)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2081 ]
  - Doctoral Students' Progress, 1995 (Box 39)
    [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2070 ]
  - Recommendations and Advising, 1993-2005 (Box 39)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series, 1954-2008 (2 linear feet) is made up of ten subseries of varied content; Brace, Mary L., Dendrograms, Krapina, Oceania, Research Travel, Samurai, University of Auckland, University of California Santa Barbara, University of Colorado, University of Hawaii, University of Michigan, Department of Anthropology, Creation Evolution Debate, Korean Studies Committee, and Museum of Anthropology.
  - Brace, Mary L. (Box 27)
    - Brace, Mary L., undated (Box 27)
    - Brace, Mary L. -- Drawings, undated (Box 27)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 27)
    - Ainu (Box 27)
    - An Indonesian Selematan, 1991 (Box 27)
    - Essay on Chinese Cooking: What Makes it Chinese?, 1991 (Box 27)
    - Beverages in China: What the Chinese like to Drink, 1992 (Box 27)
    - American Perceptions on Asian Cuisines, 1993 (Box 27)
    - A Japanese Noshing Party, undated (Box 27)
  - Dendrograms
    - 2003, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Krapina
    - Revision, 1978 (Box 27)
    - Data, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Oceania (Box 28)
    - 1988 (Box 28)
    - Working Data (Box 28)
    - Oceanic Tooth Size -- Correspondence (Box 28)
    - Oceanic Tooth Size -- Variations as a Reflection of Biological and Cultural Mixing (Box 28)
    - Tooth Reduction in the Orient (Box 28)
  - Research Travel
    - Africa, 1968 (Box 28)
    - Japan and China, 1979 (Box 28)
    - China, 1980 (Box 28)
    - China -- Correspondence, 1980 (Box 28)
    - China Teeth -- Prehistoric and Human Tooth Size, 1980 (Box 28)
    - China, 1982 (Box 28)
    - China, 1983 (Box 28)
    - China, 1984 (Box 28)
    - China, 1985 (Box 28)
    - China, 1986 (Box 28)
    - Skandinavia, 1986 (Box 28)
    - Europe, 1987 (Box 28)
    - China, 1988 (Box 28)
    - Europe, 1988; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Europe -- correspondence, 1988 (Box 28)
    - China INQUA, 1991 (Box 28)
    - China, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Israel, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Greece, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Italy, 1992 (Box 28)
    - Egypt, 1996 (Box 28)
  - Samurai, 1986-1989 (Box 28)
  - University of Auckland, New Zea, 1973 (Box 28)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara
    - Molnar, 1965-1966 (Box 28)
    - University of Colorado, Boulder, 1966-1967 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Teaching Materials -- Anthro 151 and 566 (Box 29)
    - Publications, 1954-1970 (Box 29)
    - Anthropology (Geological), 1963 (Box 29)
    - On the Race Concept, 1963 (Box 29)
    - Prentice Hall, 1963 (Box 29)
    - A Non-Racial Approach to the Understanding of Human Diversity, 1964 (Box 29)
    - Fate of the Classic Neanderthals, 1964 (Box 29)
    - Experimental Studies in Human Tooth Wear, 1965 (Box 29)
    - Mount Carmel Fossils, 1965 (Box 29)
    - Problem of the Neanderthals, undated (Box 29)
  - University of Colorado, Boulder, Summer Institute in Anthropology, 1971 (Box 29)
  - University of Hawaii
    - 1979 (Box 29)
    - Anthro 215, 1979-1980 (Box 29)
  - University of Michigan
    - Debate on Creation/ Evolution
      - Creation, 1981-1991; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Creation vs Evolution debate, 1982; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Creation, 1995 (Box 29)
      - Creation vs Evolution debate recordings, 1982; 2 audiocassettes (Box 39)
    - Department of Anthropology
      - 1975-1982 (Box 39)
      - 1979-1994 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2024 ]
      - Bio Anthropology-China-1995 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2025 ]
      - Bio Anthropology -- Graduate Affairs, 1976-1981 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2038 ]
      - 2002-2004 (Box 39)
      - Faculty, 1975 (Box 39)
      - Students, 1998 (Box 39)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2073 ]
      - 1996-1999 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2029 ]
      - 2005 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2035 ]
      - 2006-2008 (Box 39)
    - Korean Studies Search Committee, 1996 (Box 39)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2026 ]
    - Library Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 39)
    - Museum of Anthropology
      - 1973-1976 (Box 39)
      - 1980-1986 (Box 39)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 39)
      - Future Leadership, 2007 (Box 39)
      - 2000-2006 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2036 ]
      - Associate Applications, 2002 (Box 39)
      - Executive Committee, 1996-2008 (Box 39)
      - Publications Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 39)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2033 ]
      - Research, 1970-2000 (Box 39)
- Kennewick
  - Correspondence
    The Kennewick series, 1996-2008 (4.5 linear feet) contains documentation developed around the Kennewick Man case and research. The documents in this series include extensive correspondence and informative material to and from Alan Schneider and the firm representing eight anthropologists involved in the legal battle. Some legal documentation is also included, as well as email correspondence with colleagues, interviewers, researchers, and other people regarding Kennewick Man. There are a small number of folders with publications Brace was involved in concerning the same topic. A folder of news clippings also provides additional information on the nine year controversy.
    - Barran Liebman Attorneys, 2000 (Box 29)
    - Email, 1998-2008 (Box 29)
    - Lane et al., 1996-1998 (Box 29)
    - National Academy of Science, 2005 (Box 29)
    - Paleoindians -- Washington, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Schneider
      - October 1996 (Box 29)
      - December 1996 (Box 29)
      - January, 1997 (Box 29)
      - February, 1997 (Box 29)
      - March, 1997 (Box 29)
      - April, 1997 (Box 29)
      - May, 1997 (Box 30)
      - June, 1997 (Box 30)
      - July, 1997 (Box 30)
      - August, 1997 (Box 30)
      - September, 1997 (Box 30)
      - October, 1997 (Box 30)
      - November, 1997 (Box 30)
      - December, 1997 (Box 30)
      - January, 1998 (Box 30)
      - February, 1998 (Box 30)
      - March, 1998, 2 folders (Box 30)
      - April, 1998 (Box 30)
      - May, 1998 (Box 30)
      - June, 1998 (Box 30)
      - July, 1998 (Box 30)
      - August, 1998 (Box 30)
      - September, 1998 (Box 30)
      - October, 1998 (Box 30)
      - November, 1998 (Box 31)
      - December, 1998 (Box 31)
      - January, 1999 (Box 31)
      - February, 1999 (Box 31)
      - March, 1999 (Box 31)
      - April, 1999 (Box 31)
      - May, 1999 (Box 31)
      - June, 1999 (Box 31)
      - July, 1999 (Box 31)
      - August, 1999 (Box 31)
      - September, 1999 (Box 31)
      - October, 1999 (Box 31)
      - November, 1999 (Box 31)
      - December, 1999 (Box 31)
      - January, 2000 (Box 31)
      - February, 2000 (Box 31)
      - March, 2000 (Box 31)
    - Schneider
      - April, 2000 (Box 31)
      - May, 2000 (Box 31)
      - June, 2000 (Box 31)
      - July, 2000 (Box 31)
      - August, 2000 (Box 31)
      - October, 2000 (Box 31)
      - December, 2000 (Box 31)
      - January, 2001 (Box 31)
      - February, 2001 (Box 31)
      - March, 2001 (Box 31)
      - April, 2001 (Box 31)
      - May, 2001 (Box 32)
      - June, 2001 (Box 32)
      - July, 2001 (Box 32)
      - August, 2001 (Box 32)
      - October, 2001 (Box 32)
      - December, 2001 (Box 32)
      - January, 2002 (Box 32)
      - February, 2002 (Box 32)
      - March, 2002 (Box 32)
      - April, 2002 (Box 32)
      - May, 2002 (Box 32)
      - June, 2002 (Box 32)
      - August, 2002 (Box 32)
      - September, 2002, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - October, 2002, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - November, 2002 (Box 32)
      - December, 2002, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - January, 2003 (Box 32)
      - February, 2003 (Box 32)
      - March, 2003 (Box 32)
      - April, 2003 (Box 32)
      - May, 2003 (Box 32)
      - June, 2003 (Box 32)
      - July, 2003 (Box 32)
      - January-May, 2004 (Box 32)
      - June-August, 2004 (Box 33)
      - September-December, 2004 (Box 33)
      - January-April, 2005 (Box 33)
      - May-August, 2005 (Box 33)
      - September --, December, 2005 (Box 33)
      - January --, April, 2006 (Box 33)
      - May-July, 2006 (Box 33)
      - Nagpra --, August, 2006 (Box 33)
      - August-September, 2006 (Box 33)
      - October-December, 2006 (Box 33)
      - 2000-2008 (Box 33)
    - June Hearing, 2001
      - 2003 (Box 33)
    - News and Articles, 1996-2000 (Box 33)
    - Publications (Box 33)
    - Legal documentation -- general
      - 1996-1997 (Box 33)
      - 1997 (Box 33)
      - 2007-2008 (Box 33)
      - Kennewick Man: Perspectives on the Ancient One, 2008; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Senate Committee in Indian Affairs, 2005 (Box 33)
    - Kennewick -- The Connections of the Kennewick Paleoindian Specimen, 2005-2006; 2 folders (Box 33)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series, 1969-1984? (4 linear feet) is made up, for the most part, of color slides. Other materials found are some illustrations, negatives, prints, a few maps, and DVDs with digital scans of crania and bones, a small number of transparencies, and some X-Rays housed as oversize materials. Among these materials there are 27 Kodak slide boxes that are part of a group. These boxes are numbered and the slides have some minimal description of the content. The majority of materials show crania, bones, teeth and mandibles. For most of the contents here there is limited date and context information.
  - Ainu Atsuga (Box 34)
  - Australian Aboriginal (Box 34)
  - Arago (Box 34)
  - Atlas Negatives (Box 34)
  - Bones and Meeting (Box 34)
  - Brace, C. Loring (Box 34)
  - Brace -- Negatives (Box 34)
  - Brace and Skulls (Box 34)
  - Gibraltar and Rhodesian (Box 34)
  - Illustrations (Box 34)
  - Lucy (Box 34)
  - Sevapithecus (Box 34)
  - Skulls negatives 85-B1 -- B20, 1985 (Box 34)
  - Skulls negatives and contacts, 84-B1 -- 84-B16 (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Prints and Negatives, 1983 (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Prints (Box 34)
  - Skulls and Travel Transparencies (Box 34)
  - Skulls Negatives (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Prints and Negatives (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Prints (Box 34)
  - Skulls (Box 34)
  - Skulls (Box 34)
  - Skulls and Graph Images (DVD), DVD (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Prints and Transparencies (Box 34)
  - Skulls -- Negatives and Prints (Box 34)
  - Symposium Papers -- Graphs and Negatives (Box 34)
  - Quafzeh (Box 34)
  - Slides, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Assorted slides, 13 boxes (Box 35)
  - Slides -- Mus칠e de L'Homme, Krapina, Aqfa, Laugerie Haute, 1 boxes (Box 35)
  - Kunji Cave, 1 boxes (Box 35)
  - Slides Box A -- Hawaii, China, France, Switzerland, Asia (Box 36)
  - Slides Box B -- China, Japan, Indians (Native Americans) (Box 36)
  - Slides Box C-Maps, Krapina, Qafzeh, Olduvai, Basque (Box 36)
  - Slides Box D -- Hawaii, Japan, Africa, Eastern Europe, Asia, Krapina, Post. Pleistocene (Box 36)
  - Numbered Slide boxes #2 -- 34 (missing 1, 5, 8, 11, 12, 14, 22) (Box 37)
  - AMNH, 1982 (Box 37)
  - Arago (Box 37)
  - Bones, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Kafzeh, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Omo, 2 boxes (Box 37)
  - Q (Box 37)
  - Skulls, 1984 (Box 37)
  - Kodak boxes, 4 boxes (Box 37)
  - Assorted Slides, 21 boxes (Box 37)
  - Canibal II [Cam Actuated Nibbling Appliance?]-Safety Film (Box 37)
  - Slide Boxes, 2 boxes (Box 37)
  - Power Phase Indians, undated; oversize (Box 38)
  - Kenyapithecus, 1967; oversize